Use of technology in sports is supposed to be able to provide accurate and instant feedback, with better decision-making and reduced errors compared to human intervention.
体育运动中使用科技被认为能够提供准确即时的反馈，相比人工干预能更好地做出决策以及少出错误。
But is that always the case?
但情况总是如此吗？
The annual tennis tournament Wimbledon made the decision this year to replace their line judges.
一年一度的温布尔登网球锦标赛今年决定更换他们的线审。
These have traditionally been men and women who judge whether the ball is in or out of bounds, but they were switched out for AI that analyses camera footage, which should be faster and more accurate.
传统上，线审是判断球是否出界的男女性裁判，但他们被分析摄像机画面的人工智能取代了，后者应该更快、更准确。
Despite this, the electronic line calling system failed just a week into the 2025 championship.
尽管如此，电子司线系统在2025年锦标赛开赛仅一周后就出现了故障。
The ball-tracking technology was turned off by a person accidentally.
球迹追踪技术被一个人不慎关闭。
This meant a point had to be replayed, which resulted in Sonay Kartal controversially winning the game.
这意味着必须重赛一分，导致索奈·卡塔尔富有争议地赢得了比赛。
If technology needs humans to operate it in the first place, whose fault is it in situations like these where things go wrong?
如果首先需要人类来操作科技，那么在诸如此类出现问题的情形中，这又是谁的错呢？
In football, referees often come under fire for their decision-making.
在足球比赛中，裁判常常因其决策而受到批评。
But VAR, that's 'video assistant referee', is regularly used in football these days too.
但如今足球比赛中也经常使用VAR，即"视频助理裁判"。
A referee can ask for a VAR check, which means that if they are unsure of something, like the awarding of a penalty, they can double-check their own judgement.
裁判可以要求VAR检查，这意味着如果他们不确定某件事，比如是否判罚点球，他们可以再次检查自己的判断。
However, last football season, VAR made oversights which angered a lot of managers, players and fans.
然而，上个足球赛季，VAR出现了一些疏漏，激怒了许多教练、球员和球迷。
They said the system was not fit for purpose and even favoured some teams over others.
他们说这个系统不合适，甚至偏袒某些球队。
Despite this, the Premier League's chief football officer, Tony Scholes, said during the middle of last year's season that standards were actually higher than ever.
尽管如此，英超首席足球官托尼·斯科尔斯在上赛季中期表示，标准实际上比以往任何时候都高。"
"Before VAR, 82% of the decisions made were deemed to be correct.
在VAR引入之前，82%的判罚被认为是正确的。
In the season so far, that figure is 96%," he said.
在本赛季到目前为止，这个数字是96%，"他说。
So, why do we still not trust technology if it often improves a situation?
那么，如果技术常常有助于情况的改善，为什么我们仍然不信任它呢？
Professor Gina Neff from Cambridge University says that we have a very strong, in-built sense of fairness.
剑桥大学的吉娜·内夫教授说，我们有一种非常强烈的、内在的公平感。"
"The machine makes decisions based on the set of rules it's been programmed to adjudicate," she said.
机器根据提前编程的规则做出决定和裁决，"她说。"
"Right now, in many areas where AI is touching our lives, we feel like humans understand the context much better than the machine."
目前，在人工智能触及我们生活的诸多领域中，我们觉得人类比机器更了解背景与环境。"
Whether you trust it or not, technology is here to stay, including in the world of sport.
无论你是否信任，技术都将存在，包括在体育界。